

About Me

Hi, this is Fan Suen, a UX designer working in Shanghai, I got interested in software design since college, learning and engaging in it for years. I'm particularly experienced in business software design. I have tackled difficult design challenges, mentored teams and shipped products with great UX.

I achieve results by recognizing the underlying patterns in a design that can make or break a design. I understand what can be dropped, what needs to be retained, and what needs to be developed. Finally, I know how to package design requirements for developers to make great products.

With basic knowledge of html and css, I'm good at build relationships with engineering teams and push things forward, I'm very willing to try new things, not only UX design jobs, also open to roles like product manager or product designer.

If you want to know more about me, please visit my personal website http://fansuen.com

Experience

Design Manager @ IngageApp (2018.04 - Present)

Leading UX teams through planning, research, strategy development, concept and product definition as well as all phases of design. Define design guidelines and deliver great UX solutions to PaaS and CRM products. Working closely with PMs, developers, engineers to ensure design consistency and high quality of implementation across multiple product lines.

Senior UX Designer @ Alibaba Group (2017.07 - 2018.04)

Product owner and designer of a Interface builder called Aimake, by which anyone can easily build real interfaces using front-end components with drag&drop. Conduct and drive product strategic and design decisions. Key designer of Risk Management softwares and Safety Compliance system over electronic business platform, execute all design stages from concept to final hand-off to engineering.

UX/UI Designer @ SAP SME (2014.09 - 2017.07)

Central designer of SAP Anywhere, responsible for building design guidelines, UX patterns, UI Kit and UI frameworks. Design owner of multiple function models like central design topics, BI analytics, multi-channel management. In charge of design Inbox app, PoS app and Anywhere E-Shop which are within Anywhere eco-system.

UX/UI Design Intern @ SAP CI&SP (2014.03 - 2014.09)

Responsible for design an intelligent distribution system for shipping containers named TRP(Transportation Resource Planning) running on SAP HANA. Apply "Design Thinking" to design process. Learning deep into SAP Fiori Design Guideline and adopt it in solving complex product requirements.

Design History Researcher @ Nobel (2012.12 - 2013.12)

Participate in the research of "Chinese Industrial Design History", "Chinese Industrial Design Archives", responsible for data collation and content writing. Author of "Shanghai support national Industry Construction from the 1950s" and published in core journals.

Education

Industrial Design - Master @ ECUST (2012.09 - 2014.11)

Major in Product Design and Design History, main courses are design theory, design construction, design management, Interaction design, design psychology, design history. Design websites and mobile apps for start-up companies.

Industrial Design Engineering - Bachelor @ Jiangsu University (2008.09 - 2012.07)

Major in Industrial Design Engineering, main courses are ergonomics, design science, aesthetics, mechanical engineering, sketch, 3d modeling and vehicle design. Design and build portal for local companies.

Contact Me

+86 188 1823 7108 fansuen@outlook.com

Skills

User Experience Design	
User Interface Design	
Interaction Design	
Usability Testing	
Web App Design	
Mobile App Design	
User-Centered Design	
Rapid Prototyping	
Information Visualization	
HTML+CSS	

Abilities

Team Management	
Project Management	
Team Leadership	
Public Speaking	
Design Strategy	
Agile Methodologies	

Languages

Mandarin	
English (CET-6)	

Hobbies

```
design product travel
social science history art
android iOS car
technology
```

